<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<opportunities>
	<opportunity title="BREAK" posted="2014 - 2015"></opportunity>
	<opportunity title="Code NOW" posted="8 JAN 15" logo="http://codenow.org/wp-content/themes/codenow/img/navbar/CN_header_logo.gif">
		<description ><![CDATA[
			CodeNow makes learning about programming awesome with our weekend training. The course will be held at a local tech company, where you’ll learn about the programming language Ruby. Our goal is to help you understand how to program in a way that is exciting and interactive, giving you invaluable experience for your future
			<br/><br/>
			Workshops take place on Feb 7, 8 & 21 at a local tech company.  Students are taught to work together while building hands-on projects, and practice industry programming techniques. Each student receives 25 hours of training and a real understanding of what programming is.
			<br/><br/>
			Application Deadline:  Wednesday, Jan 21
			]]></description>
			<website>
				http://codenow.org/
			</website>
			<link>
				http://codenow.org/get-involved/
			</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="Hour of Code 2014" posted="08 DEC 14" logo="http://hourofcode.com/images/hour-of-code-logo.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		The Hour of Code is a global movement reaching tens of millions of students in 180+ countries during December 8-14, 2014, in celebration of Computer Science Education Week.  The Hour of Code is a one-hour introduction to computer science, designed to demystify code and show that anybody can learn the basics. <b> Ages 4 to 104.</b>
		<br/><br/>
		Below are just a few organizations hosting events in support of the Hour of Code.
		<ul>
		<li><a href="https://code.org/learn">Code.org</a></li>
		<li><a href="https://codehs.com/hourofcode/">CodeHS</a></li>
		<li><a href="https://www.apple.com/retail/code/">Apple</a></li>
		<li><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/about/corporatecitizenship/en-us/youthspark/youthsparkhub/hourofcode/">Microsoft</a></li>
		<li><a href="http://goo.gl/forms/P1ylmDjiOR">Bayside High School</a></li>
		</ul>
		<br/>
		Every student should have the opportunity to learn computer science. It helps nurture problem-solving skills, logic and creativity. By starting early, students will have a foundation for success in any 21st-century career path.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://hourofcode.com/us
		</website>
		<link>
		http://hourofcode.com/us
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="BEBRAS Computing Challenge 2014" posted="05 DEC 14" logo="images/events/bebras.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		The Bebras Computing Challenge introduces computational thinking to students. It is organized in over 30 countries and designed to get students all over the world excited about computing.  Each participant gets 45 minutes to answer 15 multiple-choice questions that focus on computational and logical thinking. It is completed online in your own school and it shows to school and student how well their skills are developed.<br/><br/>
		<b>What is computational thinking?</b><br/>
		Originally it involves a set of problem-solving skills that software engineers use to write programs and apps. You can break these skills down in smaller and more familiar components like pattern recognition, algorithm design, data analysis or abstraction. Computational thinking is used in more areas than just software, so it is very useful to get acquainted. Want to know more? Visit <a href='http://www.google.com/edu/computational-thinking/what-is-ct.html'>Computational Thinking</a>.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://www.bebraschallenge.org/
		</website>
		<link>
		http://www.bebraschallenge.org/
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="National STEM Video Game Challenge" posted="23 NOV 14" logo="http://www.stemchallenge.org/stem/generated/header-logo-stem.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		The National STEM Video Game Challenge, presented by the Smithsonian in partnership with the Joan Ganz Cooney Center and E-Line Media, opens for student submissions of original video games and game designs. The Challenge aims to motivate interest in Science, Technology, Engineering and Math (STEM) learning among youth by tapping into their natural passions for playing and making video games.<br/><br/>
		Entries can be created using any game creation platform such as Gamestar Mechanic, Unity, GameMaker and Scratch or a written game design concept document. Judges will select winners for each game creation platform in both categories. Each winner will receive computer hardware as well as game design and educational software. Each winner’s sponsoring organization will receive a cash prize of $2000.<br/><br/>
		The National STEM Video Game Challenge is accepting entries through February 25, 2015. Complete guidelines and details on how to enter are available on the website.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://www.stemchallenge.org
		</website>
		<link>
		http://www.stemchallenge.org/stem/#/student_signup_info
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="USA Computing Olympiad" posted="22 NOV 14" logo="images/events/usaco_logo.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		The USA Computing Olympiad (USACO) supports computing education in the USA and worldwide by identifying, motivating, and training pre-college students of all levels in computational problem-solving. For its 2014-2015 season, the USACO plans to offer four monthly on-line programming contests:
		<ul>
		<li>Dec 12-15: First Contest</li>
		<li>Jan 16-19: Second Contest</li>
		<li>Feb 20-23: Third Contest</li>
		<li>April 3-6: US Open (our championship contest)</li>
		</ul>
		Contests are free and open to all; they are targeted specifically at pre-college students, although others may compete as observers, ranked separately. There are three levels of difficulty: bronze (novice), silver (intermediate), and gold (advanced). All new competitors start out in the bronze level, which is designed to be accessible to students with basic programming knowledge and minimal algorithmic experience. Students earn promotion to higher levels by demonstrating excellent performance on a contest in their current level. Contests are usually 3-5 consecutive hours in duration, which students can schedule any time during a 4-day contest window. Students can submit programs in C, C++, Java, Pascal, or Python. All contests are taken individually.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://usaco.org
		</website>
		<link>
		http://usaco.org/index.php?page=register
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="EasyCTF" posted="22 NOV 14" logo="images/events/EasyCTF.jpg">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		EasyCTF is an online computer security contest targeted at middle and high school students. The contest consists of a series of challenges centered around a creative storyline where participants must reverse engineer, break, hack, decrypt, or do whatever it takes to solve the challenge and capture the flag. The challenges are all set up with the intent of being hacked, making it an excellent, legal way to get hands-on experience.
		<br/><br/>
		Singularity is an interactive game right in your browser that contains the storyline for all of the problems in the contest. Playing the game is recommended, but not required, to complete the contest. The story is set far into the future, when researchers have discovered ways to create computers that are capable of thought. After rewriting its own code, the robots have destroyed the research facility and are now on their way to destroying the world. It's up to you and your hacking skills to combat the robot and save the world!
		<br/><br/>
		From November 29 to December 6, 2014, teams of up to 5 students will play an interactive game set far into the future, <b>Singularity</b>
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://www.easyctf.com/
		</website>
		<link>
		http://www.easyctf.com/register
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="YH: Local Hack Day" posted="22 NOV 14" logo="images/events/yhlogo.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		A hack day is about celebrating the hacker community at your school by coming together and building awesome projects together! During the hack day your community will come together to create and build community together over 12 hours. MLH will be providing awesome programming and swag all day long to help celebrate all the Hacker Community everywhere.
		<br/><br/>
		Local Hack Day kicks off 9:00 am EST, December 6th, and lasts until 9:00 pm EST at <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/902+Broadway,+New+York,+NY+10010/@40.7383171,-73.9901185,18z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x89c259a3cde0617f:0x8d063ab0462e10e2">General Assembly</a> near Union Square Park, the heart of New York City. Regardless of experience level, all are welcome to come learn, celebrate and build.  Make sure to bring any hardware, laptops or smart-phones that you want to utilize during the event. We'll try really hard to get you guys access to some crazy cool hardware.
		<br/><br/>Brought to you by <a target="_blank" href="http://younghackers.us/">The Young Hackers</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://localhackday.mlh.io/">Major League Hacking</a>.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://localhackday.younghackers.us/
		</website>
		<link>
		https://younghackers.typeform.com/to/un6ui7
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="picoCTF 2014" posted="10 OCT 14" logo="images/events/picoCTF2014.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		picoCTF is a computer security game targeted at middle and high school students. The game consists of a series of challenges centered around a unique storyline where participants must reverse engineer, break, hack, decrypt, or do whatever it takes to solve the challenge. The challenges are all set up with the intent of being hacked, making it an excellent, legal way to get hands-on experience.
		<br/><br/>
		This year's competition, Oct 27 - Nov 7, features a brand new adventure. When your father disappears under strange circumstances, a flash drive is your only clue to his whereabouts. You will need to use all of the computer security skills at your disposal to uncover and decipher critical evidence. Can you solve the mystery before it's too late?
		<br/><br/>Contact Mr. Castro in person or at rcastro@baysidehigh.org.  We wish to organize teams at the school level.  In Spring 2013, Bayside High School's team Bayside Overflow placed 280 across a national field of 1938 teams.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		https://picoctf.com/
		</website>
		<link>
		https://picoctf.com/#registration
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="CodeDay New York" posted="10 OCT 14" logo="https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/378800000634893302/7d23af54986059cb8253c10f7fd00cc6.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		CodeDay is a 24-hour event where students passionate about technology get together and build cool things together! You pitch ideas, form teams, and build a cool app or game over 24 hours! We're constantly amazed by the results after CodeDay!
		<br/><br/>
		CodeDay is from Nov 8 - 9 noon to noon at the <a href='http://www.wix.com/lounge/new-york'>Wix Lounge</a> in NYC.  Bring a laptop to work on! If you can, please bring a power strip.  We'll have food, including vegetarian options.  Cost is $20.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://codeday.org/ny
		</website>
		<link>
		https://codeday.org/ny/register
		</link>
	</opportunity>

	<opportunity title="Code NOW" posted="6 OCT 14" logo="http://codenow.org/wp-content/themes/codenow/img/navbar/CN_header_logo.gif">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		What do Instagram, Snapchat and Twitter have in common? They were all created by people who knew how to code. Programming is a skill that gives you the ability to create and innovate. That’s what CodeNow is for! We introduce you to programming in a fun and interactive way.
		<br/><br/>
		Our workshops take place on Nov 8, 9 & 22 at a local tech company. During the workshop you’ll get to build fun interactive games and learn from top software engineers. If accepted, we’ll ask you to complete some puzzles and other fun activities in preparation for the workshop. After completing the workshop you’ll have a better understanding of what programming is. It will not be easy, but you’ll definitely have fun and learn a lot along the way. And we’ll provide you with all the tools and resources to get you on your way to become a great programmer.
		<br/><br/>
		Application Deadline:  Wednesday, Oct 22
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://codenow.org/
		</website>
		<link>
		http://codenow.org/get-involved/
		</link>
	</opportunity>

	<opportunity title="the itGirls Overnight Retreat" posted="29 SEP 14" logo="http://ischool.syr.edu/media/images/2014/3/itgirlslogo.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		Hosted at Syracuse University on Nov 9 - 10, 2014 in Upstate NY, the itGirls Overnight Retreat aims to expose high school women to the information science field of study. Each year, we invite about 100 high school juniors and seniors from across the nation just like YOU to come and learn more about technology, our school, and to meet other It Girls!
		<br/><br/>
		The It Girls Overnight Retreat is a two-day event loaded with fun! You will have a chance to experience a day in the life of an iSchool student, make new friends, interact with current It Girls at the iSchool who are on the verge of greatness, and network with industry leaders who are paving the way (and might one day want to hire you!). If YOU believe that you are an It Girl and would like to join us this year, applications are open now!
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://ischool.syr.edu/ilife/womenintech/theitgirls
		</website>
		<link>
		http://ischool.syr.edu/ilife/womenintech/theitgirls/apply.aspx
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="BREAK" posted="2013 - 2014"></opportunity>
	<opportunity title="HSCTF: Hacking Competition" posted="29 APR 14" logo="http://hsctf.com/images/wires-mobile.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		HSCTF, High School Capture the Flag, is a national online hacking competition designed to educate high schoolers in computer science. Capture the Flag (CTF) competitions are traditionally targeted at college students or industry professionals. HSCTF is a CTF designed for younger students who might be interested in computer science.
		<br/><br/>
		Teams of up to 4 students can compete.  Competition requires only a computer with a modern web browser.  During the competition, different challenges are released which allow the participants to reverse engineer, break, hack, decrypt, and do whatever it takes to capture that flag. When a team submits a flag to the scoring page, they will get points.
		<br/><br/>
		Competition runs from May 18th 10:00AM EST to May 25th 11:59PM EST
		]]></description>
				<website>
		http://hsctf.com/
		</website>
		<link>
		http://hsctf.com/
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="CodeDay New York" posted="30 APR 14" logo="https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/378800000634893302/7d23af54986059cb8253c10f7fd00cc6.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		CodeDay is a 24-hour event where students passionate about technology get together and build cool things together! You pitch ideas, form teams, and build a cool app or game over 24 hours!
		<br/><br/>
		We're constantly amazed by the results after CodeDay! For instance, Mohammad Adib created and published <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mohammad.adib.sidebar.lite&hl=en" target="_blank">Sidebar</a>, an Android app with over 200,000 downloads at CodeDay!
		<br/><br/>
		CodeDay is from May 24 to May 25 noon to noon at the Flatiron School in NYC.  Bring a laptop to work on! If you can, please bring a power strip.  We'll have food, including vegetarian options.  Students can receive 20% off if they use the promo code SCHOOL.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://codeday.org/ny
		</website>
		<link>
		http://www.eventbrite.com/e/codeday-spring-2014-new-york-registration-11194534153
		</link>
	</opportunity>
    <opportunity title="GenTech Spring Break Game Jam" posted="19 MAR 14" logo="http://nycgenerationtech.com/wp-content/themes/NYCGT-Yasmin/2.0/img/logo_lg.jpg">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		Calling all NYC high school students - do you like playing mobile games and want to make games of your own to show your friends? Do you have an idea that will be the 'next Flappy Birds,' but don't know how to bring it to life?
		<br/><br/>
		Presented by the Network for Teaching Entrepreneurship (NFTE), the New York City Economic Development Corporation (NYCEDC), and TreSensa, the Spring Break Game Jam aims to provide New York City high school students from under-resourced communities, the opportunity to learn about professional game development and to build related technical skills. With the support of volunteer mentors, each student team will create a mobile game that runs on the TreSensa Game Engine and a 3-min pitch presentation to showcase their work. At the end of the event, students will demo their games to judges from the tech community, and prizes will be awarded to the winning teams. We hope you can join us!
		<br/><br/>
		Please note that this a two-day event, taking place 9:00AM-8:00PM both Saturday, 4/12, and Sunday, 4/13.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://nycgenerationtech.com/
		</website>
		<link>
		http://www.eventbrite.com/e/spring-break-game-jam-registration-10802232769
		</link>
	</opportunity>
    <opportunity title="Hack NY" posted="19 MAR 14" logo="http://hackny.org/a/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/hackny_logo_small.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		 Every spring and fall, hundreds of students from scores of universities around the country flock to hackNY’s student hackathons, where they participate in collaborative and creative coding challenges in a 24-hour coding sprint. The events open with API demos from New York City startups selected by the student organizing committee, after which students work in teams to build projects based on these APIs. Students work around the clock, and the event culminates in a presentation before a panel of judges the next day. hackNY is excited to announce its ninth student hackathon on April 5th-6th at Columbia Engineering’s Fu Foundation School of Engineering and Applied Science.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://hackny.org/a/spring2014hackathon/
		</website>
		<link>
		http://www.eventbrite.com/e/spring-2014-hackny-student-hackathon-demos-tickets-10726397945
		</link>
	</opportunity>
    <opportunity title="House APP Challenge" posted="14 FEB 14" logo="http://s3.amazonaws.com/challengepost/photos/production/challenge_photos/000/076/955/datas/full_width.jpg?1393353943">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		This year marks the first annual Congressional Science, Technology, Engineering and Math (STEM) Academic Competition, the “House Student App Challenge.”  This new challenge is designed to engage student’s creativity and encourage their participation in STEM education fields.  Established by Members of the U.S. House of Representatives in 2013, this challenge is a nationwide event that allows high school students from across the country to learn by creating and exhibiting their software application, or “app,” for mobile, tablet, or computer devices on a platform of their choice. <br>
		<br>
		Throughout the challenge period, participating students will be provided opportunities to engage with various STEM educational partners located within the community to mentor and assist them with their app development. <br>
		<br>
		The “House Student App Challenge” is open to all high school students in participating districts. Students entering the competition must submit their app’s source code online during the Competition Submission Period between 12 PM Eastern Standard Time on FEBRUARY 1ST, 2014, and 12 PM Eastern Daylight Time on APRIL 30TH, 2014, as well as provide a YouTube or VIMEO video demo explaining their app and what they learned through this competition process.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://housestudentapps.challengepost.com/
		</website>
		<link>
		https://secure.challengepost.com/users/register?return_to=http%3A%2F%2Fhousestudentapps.challengepost.com%2F
		</link>
	</opportunity>
    <opportunity title="GenTech Summer Program" posted="10 FEB 14" logo="http://nycgenerationtech.com/wp-content/themes/NYCGT-Yasmin/2.0/img/logo_lg.jpg">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		In a two-week tech-entrepreneurship “bootcamp”, students learn the fundamentals of entrepreneurship; develop basic knowledge of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript; and form teams to develop a mobile app and business plan aimed at improving education or the quality of city life for NYC students.<br/><br/> Following the bootcamp, students will continue to develop their coding skills while building out their apps and business plan during weekly classroom sessions and twice-weekly evening mentoring sessions from July-August.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://nycgenerationtech.com/
		</website>
		<link>
		http://nycgenerationtech.com/apply/
		</link>
	</opportunity>
    <opportunity title="edX" posted="10 FEB 14" logo="https://www.edx.org/sites/default/files/theme/edx-logo-header.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		edX courses are designed to be interesting, fun and rigorous. They are the best courses, from the best professors and the best schools, spanning dozens of subjects. Some edX courses now offer ID verified Certificates of Achievement. A new way to demonstrate your achievement and showcase your knowledge. <br/><br/>

		edX offers interactive online classes and Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs) from the world’s best universities. Online courses from MITx, HarvardX, BerkeleyX, UTx and many other universities. Topics include biology, business, chemistry, computer science, economics, finance, electronics, engineering, food and nutrition, history, humanities, law, literature, math, medicine, music, philosophy, physics, science, statistics and more. EdX is a non-profit online initiative created by founding partners Harvard and MIT.
		]]></description>
		<website>
		https://www.edx.org/course-list/allschools/allsubjects/allcourses
		</website>
		<link>
		https://courses.edx.org/register
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="Girls Who Code: Summer Immersion Program" posted="07 FEB 14" logo="http://girlswhocode.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Press_GWC-Square-Logo.png">

		<description ><![CDATA[
		Launched in Spring 2012, Girls Who Code is a national nonprofit organization working to close the gender gap in the technology and engineering sectors. With support from public and private partners, Girls Who Code works to educate, inspire, and equip high school girls with the skills and resources to pursue opportunities in computing fields.<br/><br/>

The Girls Who Code Summer Immersion Program represents an innovative approach to computer science education, pairing seven weeks of intensive instruction in robotics, web design, and mobile development with engaging, career-focused mentorship and exposure led by the industry's top female entrepreneurs and engineers.

		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://girlswhocode.com/programs/
		</website>
		<link>
		http://girlswhocode.com/applynow/
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="GenTech Student Hackathon: Code4Tomorrow" posted="04 FEB 14" logo="http://ebmedia.eventbrite.com/s3-build/images/4369715/57053281795/1/logo.jpg">
		<description ><![CDATA[
		GenTech Student Hackathon: Code4Tomorrow challenges students to identify ways to make a positive change in the communities in which they live and to think about solutions for big social problems related to health, education, employment, and seniors. With the support of volunteer mentors, students will create a digital prototype, promotional website, and demo presentation to showcase their idea. In the evening, all students will present, and prizes will be awarded to the winning teams. We hope you can join us!<br/><br/>
		NYC Generation Tech (GenTech) student hackathons aim to provide NYC high school students from under-resourced communities the opportunity to develop their coding skills and work alongside professionals from NYC’s tech community.

		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://nycgenerationtech.com/
		</website>
		<link>
		http://www.eventbrite.com/e/gentech-student-hackathon-code4tomorrow-registration-10124531747
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="CodeNOW" posted="01 FEB 14" logo="http://blog.awesomefoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/codenow-logo-sm1.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
What do Instagram, Snapchat and Twitter have in common? They were all created by people who knew how to code. Programming is a skill that gives you the ability to create and innovate. How cool would it be to take an idea and watch it come to life through programming? All it takes is the willingness to try something new, and the dedication to work at it. That’s what CodeNow is for!  We introduce you to programming in a fun and interactive way.<br/><br/>

Our workshops take place in San Francisco and New York City on the weekends at local tech companies, and are led by top software engineers. Accepted students will be given puzzles and activities to complete before the workshop. Those who complete the workshop will have an opportunity to continue with CodeNow and earn a laptop. It will not be easy, but you’ll definitely have fun and learn a lot along the way. And we’ll provide you with all the tools and resources to get you on your way to become a great programmer.<br/><br/>

Does this sound like fun and something you might be interested in? We’re currently accepting applications which are due on February 5th. If selected, you’ll receive a scholarship worth $250 in order to attend the program. Which means it’s free and you get to brag to all your friends!
		]]></description>
		<website>
		http://codenow.org
		</website>
		<link>
		http://codenow.org/apply/
		</link>
	</opportunity>
	<opportunity title="Stanford Online" posted="06 FEB 14" logo="https://class.stanford.edu/static/themes/stanford/images/stanford-S-logo.ac1a37d62c92.png">
		<description ><![CDATA[
Stanford University is developing new online course material in order to improve on-campus courses and provide broader public access to exciting learning opportunities. The engineering team at Stanford's office of the Vice Provost for Online Learning is running and developing on an instance of the OpenEdX platform. Courses are totally free and offer certificates of completion from Stanford University.  <br/><br/>Starts 06 JAN 14 - Introduction to Databases.<br/>
Starts 21 JAN 14 - Introduction to Computer Networking </br>
		]]></description>
		<website>
		https://class.stanford.edu/
		</website>
		<link>
		https://class.stanford.edu/register
		</link>
	</opportunity>
</opportunities>
